

Faisal Aljaghthami Software Engineer

+966549024660

fayeharbi@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/faisalaljaghathami/

Jeddah - Saudi Arabia

18/03/2000

Summary

A senior Software Engineering student at the University of Jeddah, with a Nanodegree in UX Design, and a 1+ years of experience in UX/ UI Design, Web Development, Quality Assurance, Public Relations.

Interested in researching new ideas and techniques to create impactful experiences for users through UX/UI. Ambitious, cheerful, observant, and love to learn new skills and go through new experiences.

Skills

- UX/UI Design
- Web Development
- Public Relations
- Figma
- Project Management
 - Jira
- Quality Assurance
- Microsoft Office

Education

Sep 2018 - May 2023

Software Engineering



University of Jeddah

- GPA: 4.55/5
 - Houners Class.
 - · Vice President of the "Future Leaders Committee".
 - Public Relations Specilist at Google Developer Student Clubs UJ.

Licenses & Certificates

UX Design Nanodegree

Udacity

Project Management Professional Certificate

Google

Data Analytics Professional Certificate

Google

Work Experiences

Mar 2022 - Jun 2022

Web Developer

Avant Gaea

- Designed and built a responsive B2C E-commerce platform using HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript.
- Daily maintenance of code, debugging issues, and solving clients' problems.
- Led my team and collaborated with the project management team to deliver the project on time and with the highest standards.

Jan 2022 - Mar 2022

Quality Assurance Engineer

Brainnest

- Identified bugs impacting critical user flows by exploratory testing and error guessing, and documented problems to improve user experience.
- · Performed defect tracking and management using "Jira".
- · Developed and maintained test cases and test suites using "Qase.io".

Sep 2021 - Dec 2021

UX/UI Designer

Etiq Al

- · Re-designed the dashboard and developed 2-3 prototypes per week to improve UX and data readability.
- · Conducted and created several use cases on over 5,000 records to implement visualizations of data into the dashboard.
- · Tested and analyzed more than 3 systems to compare with our current one, and presented my findings in a clear and concise manner to key decision-makers.

Jul 2021 - Present

Public Relations Specialist

Google Developer Student Clubs UJ

- · Managed and coordinated more than 6 online sessions on IT-related topics for students.
- · Managed the process of validating and sending more than 200 certificates for students and instructors.
- · Managed the process of contacting offices in Jeddah to hold our in-person sessions.

Sep 2015 - Present

Mawhiba Fellow

King Abdulaziz Foundation for Giftedness and Creativity "Mawhiba"

- · A Mawhiba Ambassador at the "Talent Ambassadors Program".
- · Nominated by Mawhiba to participate in two international programs that took place in CA, Berkeley, and MA, Boston.
- Selected as the top 2% of all students in my year according to Mawhiba's Multiple-Cognitive Aptitude test, with a score of 97.72%